# Fadi Haddad

Phoenix, AZ

(562)-547-7954 haddad207@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/haddad207/

# **DEV-OPS ENINGEER**

Highly competent DevOps Engineer with over 2 years of professional experience. Driven by the thrill for knowledge, complex problem solving and an enthusiastic mindset. With a proficient ability in translating business requirements into software solutions. Constantly enhancing my area of expertise with online courses. Reliable and responsible team player, dedicated for personal and team growth.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

DirecTV Dec 2021 - Jul 2023

### Platform Engineer (DevOps)

Los Angeles, CA

- Administrated an instance of Jenkins: updating Jenkins to latest version, backing up Jenkins' jobs and configuration files, maintaining credentials, managing plugins, and troubleshooting issues/bugs.
- Collaborated with other departments to facilitate successful application deployments.
- Refactored a collection of Java applications that were built using ant/lvy/Gradle by adding Maven as an additional mean for compilation to integrate security scanning tools.
- Received a Connection's Award for outstanding performance for refactoring the majority of applications with minimal help from application developers.
- Enhanced application security by routinely scanning applications for vulnerabilities (CVEs). (Fortify, Sonatype: Nexus)
- Visualized application vulnerability reports via AWS QuickSight.
- With the aim to reduce company costs, started developing an implementation of a serverless cloud based solution for automated application deployment via AWS. Fully developed with Python. Projected company cost reduction of \$490,000 (AWS Lambda, AWS API Gateway, AWS Step Functions, AWS Batch Jobs, Ansible Tower and VMware).

InCube Oct 2020 - May 2021
Software Developer Amman, Jordan

- Re-developed a transit mobile application using Flutter for Emirates, Ajman.
- Developed a proof of delivery blueprint application using Flutter (frontend mobile) and .NET (backend). All while collaborating with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones.
- Developed a dynamic survey module using Flutter, which can be integrated into any existing application.
- Learned how to manage microservices with Docker and Kubernetes using Microsoft Azure.
- Before company departure, set up a framework for future employers. Trained a team of three developers to a proficient level in Flutter.

### **SKILLS**

Languages & Frameworks: C#, JavaScript, Python, TypeScript, Java, C++, HTML, CSS, .NET, Node.js, Django, Express.js, React.js, Redux, Flutter, Dart, Kotlin, Bootstrap, and Material UI.

Databases & Request handling: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, mySQL, AWS DynamoDB, MSSQL, API, RESTful API and JSON.

Tools & Platforms: AWS, Microservices, Linux, Ansible Tower, Jenkins, Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, Git, Jira, and Confluence.

### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor's in Computer Science: 2015-2020

California State University of Los Angeles

Honors Graduate with a 3.449 GPA

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner React - The Complete Guide	AWS UDEMY	React, NodeJS, Express & MongoDB - The MERN Fullstack Guide	UDEMY
The Complete Guide The Complete Node.js Developer	UDEMY	Microservices with Node JS and React	UDEMY
Unreal Engine 5 C++ Developer: Learn C++ & Make Video Games	UDEMY	More and not limited to: Flutter, UI/UX, DevOps, AI, Machine learning, Neural Networks etc	UDEMY

# **PROJECTS**

#### Krowd:

• A location based attendance mobile application, with the main goal of helping prevent students from skipping class. Developed using Kotlin and Firebase. (https://github.com/haddad207/Krowd)

### The Argive:

 A social media website for the LGBTQ+ community, that allows its users to share their experience anonymously by location via dropping pins on a map. Developed using Python (Django), React.js and PostgresSQL. (https://thearqive.com/)